Hello everyone, you all are very welcome.
You're looking at you the rear.  I am
your personal advisor Amit Raj Sharma.
In today's video we will understand the details of Insta Digit Plan of Aditya Birla Sun Life
Insurance Company Limited.
This plan is a
non-linked non-participating individual
life pure risk premium term
insurance plan.  In simple words,
you select a summarised value
for a particular term.  On that basis, you
continuously pay the premium to the company on the
basis of which you are given a life insurance.
If something happens to you within the term you select,
death benefits are given to your nominee.
Like every plan, the free lookup period in this plan is also
30 days.
If you do
not agree with the terms and conditions of the plan or
are dissatisfied with them, you can cancel the policy and get a refund within 30 days from the date you receive the policy bond.
Let us know about the eligibility criteria of
Insta DG Term Plan of Aitya Birls Sunl Life Insurance Company.  The
minimum entry age limit for taking Insta DG Term Plan is 21 years and the
maximum is 59 years, that is, people up to 59 years can
take this plan.  One can remain
under the cover till the minimum age of 23 years.
You will be able to remain under the cover till the maximum age of 61 years.  The
sum assured limit in Insta Digitum plan is
minimum ₹25 lakh and maximum
₹2 crore.
Not more than this.  There are two options for the premium payment term in the plan.
Limited premium
payment terms of 5 years and 10 years.  Regular
premium payment term ranging from 2 years to
15 years.  That is, the minimum policy term
you will get in the limited premium payment term.
Premium payment term plus 5 years
means if the premium payment term is 5
years then add 5 more years i.e. 10 years up to a
maximum of 40 years.
In case of regular premium payment term, the policy term ranges from 2 years to 15
years.
If we talk about discount, if you
are male or transgender, then you
get a discount of 7% on the first annual premium.
If you are a woman, you will
get a discount of 9% on the first premium of the year.  This will be applicable only
if your annual income is at least ₹3 lakh
and this discount will be applicable only on the first year premium.
Right?  Let us know
about the rider options of Aditya Birla Sun Life Insurance Company Limited.  So
you get the option of four riders.
First Surgical Care Rider, second Hospital
Care Rider, third Accidental Death Benefit
Rider Plus, fourth Waiver of Premium Rider.
You
can find videos about all four of these riders inside the Rider playlist.
You should check the rider playlist.
If you don't
find the video in the description of the link video, please write the rider's name in the comment section.
Let us now talk
about its grace period.  If you
pay the premium in monthly installments, you get a grace period of 15 days.  A
grace period of 30 days is available along with annual half-yearly quarterly.
The death benefit in the Insta Digitum plan of Aditya Billa Sir Life Insurance Company Limited is the
sum assured on death, which
you will compare by calculating 11 times your annual premium, taking
out 105% of the base premium paid till the date of death and then
comparing it with the absolute amount
assured to be paid, that is, the sum assured
amount you have chosen while taking the plan,
whichever is higher among the three will be the
death benefit.  The policy will terminate after the death benefit is paid.  For example, the
policy brochure
says:  Suppose if you
are Mr. Sharma and your age is 30 years.  If
you have taken Aditya Birla Sunlife Insurance's
Insta Digit Term Plan for a sum of ₹1
crore, taken a policy term of 30 years
and a premium
payment term of 10 years, then the annual base
premium you will pay will be ₹16910
and the total premium paid will be ₹16900 within 10 years.  That
means by
paying ₹16900 you will
get a life cover of ₹1 crore.  That is,
if death occurs in the 25th year of the policy term or even before that, the
sum assured
amount of ₹1 crore will be given to the nominee and the
policy will be discontinued.  Along with this, some
more examples have also been given in the policy brochure
where it is said that you are healthy.   If
you do not smoke and are
eligible for a sum assured of ₹1 crore,
wish to remain covered till the age of 60, and opt for a premium
payment term of 10 years, then if you opt for a
sum assured of ₹50 lakh and are
25 years old, your annual base premium will be
₹973.  If you are 35 years old
then the annual base premium will be
₹1925.  Premium payment for 10 years for a sum of Rs 50 lakh
and you will remain
under cover till the age of 60 years.  Same thing, if your
age is 45 years then it will be
14868.  At the same time, if at the age of 45,
you get a settlement of ₹1 crore, then
you will pay ₹27170 annually for 10 years
and will remain under the cover till the age of 60.
As per the example which
is on the screen.  If you are 35 years old, then
with the same conditions, i.e.,
if you remain under the cover till the age of 60, you will pay ₹19,760 for 10 years.
If you take a sum assured of ₹2 crore at the
age of 35 years, then the
annual base premium will be ₹33,630 for the next
10 years.  ₹42,560 at the age of 45 years.
You can pause and read the rest.
You can see everything on the screen.
Tax is not involved in this and discount
is also not involved.
We will give you its PDF on Twitter channel the day after tomorrow.   On
this note, please like and share the video
because more than 96% of the people are
neither subscribing nor liking
nor sharing the video
and the 4% of the people who have
subscribed have not turned on the notification bell.
So please do it friend.
This will provide some support to the channel and
you will get the latest videos on time.
Thank you.
[applause]
[music]